Finding Aid for the Puryear-Rodes Family Letters
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Puryear-Rodes Family Letters
1892-1997
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0737
2.50 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
This small collection of letters and transcripts is comprised of 1.04 linear feet of manuscript material, ranging in date from 1892 until the death of Sara Puryear Rodes on August 21, 1997.
Other important dates for this collection are the time around the wedding of Sara Puryear and Allan Battle Rodes on October 8, 1929.
This collection of correspondence chronicles the everyday business and lives of Sara Puryear Rodes and her husband Allan Battle Rodes and their daughter Sally. It includes letters from friends and other family members. The collection numbers approximately 230 letters.
Biographical Notes
Sara McKennie Puryear Rodes was born in 1900 and died on August 21, 1997 at the age of 97. She was a native of Nashville and lived all her life in middle Tennessee. She was the daughter of Gustavus Adolphus Puryear (1850-1936) and Rena McKennie Puryear. She graduated from Miss Annie Allison’s Girls Preparatory School in 1918. She received her BA from Vanderbilt in 1922 where she was a member of Tri Delta Sorority and the YWCA cabinet. She had a sister and two brothers all of whom attended Vanderbilt. She married Allan Battle Rodes on October 8, 1929, and they had one daughter Sara Rodes Lee, Sally, who was born on January 5, 1932.
She was a member of West End Methodist Church, a member of the Query Club, co-director of Camp Monterey for 44 years and secretary for the Cumberland Science museum for more than 50 years. She was president of the YWCA in Nashville during World War II, a founding member of Cheekwood Botanical Gardens, and a Daughter of the American Revolution.
Allan Battle Rodes, (known as Battle) was the son of H. E. Rodes and Mary Battle Rodes. He received his BA from Vanderbilt in 1924. He married Sara Puryear on October 8, 1929, and they had one daughter Sara Rodes Lee who was born in 1932. He was a business man with his own company Franklin Building Supply. In the early years of their marriage he travelled often on business. He died on January 20, 1989. Many of the letters in this collection were written by him to his wife, Sara.
Sara Rodes Lee (Sally) lives with her husband John Lee, an architect, in Williamson County. They have 3 children.
She grew up in Nashville, and received BA (1953), MA(1956) and her Ph.D (1989) degrees from Vanderbilt. She divides her time between horses and writing, and she has taught English literature at Middle Tennessee State University.
Sally Lee is the donor of this collection, and prepared the transcripts of the letters.
- Correspondence
  - 1892 (1) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1911 (1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1915 (3) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1918 (1) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1923 (1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1924 (1) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1925 (2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1926 (3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1927 (3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1928 (2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - January 21, 1929 - March 20, 1929 (6) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - March 21, 1929 - April 15, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April 15, 1929 - April 22, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - April 22, 1929 - April 26, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - April 28, 1929 - April 30, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - May 6, 1929 - May 15, 1929 (4) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - June 9, 1929 - July 16, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - September 6, 1929 - September 18, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - September 20, 1929 - September 26, 1929 (5) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - October 7, 1929; wedding invitation for October 8, 1929 (2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - January 19, 1930 - June 21, 1930 (5) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - January 21, 1950 - July 25, 1930 (5) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - July 25, 1930 - July 29, 1930 (5) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - July 29, 1930 - November 19, 1930 (4) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - November 21, 1930 - November 26, 1930 (5) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - December 4, 1930 - December 19, 1930 (5) and undated (5) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1931 (7) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - January 24, 1932 - December 11, 1932 (2) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Correspondence
  - February 2, 1933 - March 1, 1933 (5) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - March 3, 1933 - December 27, 1933 (6) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - January 2, 1934 - January 10, 1934 (8) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - January 24, 1934 - January 30, 1934 (4) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - January 31, 1934 - February 9, 1934 (6) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - October 18, 1934 - October 22, 1934 (5) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - October 23, 1934 - October 27, 1934 (5) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - November 14, 1934 - November 18, 1934 (5) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - November 19, 1934 - November 23, 1934 (5) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - November 27, 1934 - date unknown (7) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1935 (1) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1936 (13) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1938 (10) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1939 (3) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1941 (7) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1942 (3) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1943 (3) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1944 (4) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1946 (12) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1958 (2) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1963 (2) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1964 (3) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1969 (1) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1981 (1) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1983 (1) (Box 2, Folder 258)
  - 1986 (1) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1989 (1) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1990 (1) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1997 (3) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Undated letters (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Transcripts
  - 1892 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1911 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1915 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1918 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - no originals, transcripts only, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1923 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1924 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1925 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1926 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1927 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1928 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1929 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1931 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1932 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1933 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1935 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1936 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1938 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1942 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1943 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1945 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1946 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1989; 1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1997 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Additional notes by Sally Rodes Lee on the letters from 1934 and 1936 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Photographs
  - Sara P. Rodes and Sally Rodes, Delray Beach, Florida, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Ken and Jim Goodpasture, Sally Rodes, Jean Puryear, Delray Beach, Florida, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 39)